Charles M. Kurtz
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Financial Material, 1870-1989, undated, Series 5:
  - Inventories and Price Lists of Kurtz's Collections, 1870-1989, undated, 5.1:
    - List of paintings owned by Charles M. Kurtz and stored in the St. Louis Museum of Fine Arts, 1900-05 (Reel 4821, Frame 272-273)
    - List of medals and plaques lent by Charles M. Kurtz to the Albright Art Gallery, 1907 (Reel 4821, Frame 274-276)
    - List of paintings actually sold at Charles M. Kurtz estate sale (not bought by Mrs. Kurtz), 1910 (Reel 4821, Frame 277-280)
    - List of paintings in the Charles M. Kurtz collection and date acquired (Reel 4821, Frame 281-283)
    - Prices from the Charles M. Kurtz estate sale [February 24, 1910] (Reel 4821, Frame 284-286)
    - Prices of paintings bought in by Mrs. C.M. Kurtz (Reel 4821, Frame 287)
    - Inventory of paintings in Kurtz home, Sept. 27, 1910 [rewritten by Isabel Kurtz, c. 1980s] (Reel 4821, Frame 288-90)
    - Inventory notes by Isabel Kurtz, 1989 (Reel 4821, Frame 291)
    - Appraisal of paintings in Kurtz collection, 1977 (Reel 4821, Frame 292)
    - List of paintings in Kurtz house and in storage, 1980-1986 with list of 19 transparencies (Reel 4821, Frame 293-307)
  - Ledgers, 1877-1909, 5.2:
    - Ledger-list of paintings offered for sale by Charles M. Kurtz with record of provenance, 1877-1909 (Reel 4821, Frame 310-368)
    - Financial Ledger containing information on paintings by Glasgow School, 1884-1909 (Reel 4821, Frame 369-401)
    - Financial Ledger "Charles M. Kurtz in Account with Catalogue Sales-Art Gallery" re: Southern Exposition at Louisville, Ky.--records of receipts from daily admissions, catalogue sales, and pictures sold; record of pictures sold to the Kentucky Polytechnic Society in 1883, and to individuals in 1884-1886, 1883-1886 (Reel 4821, Frame 402-439)
    - Letter from Secretary of American Art Association, Katharine Timpson re: error in statement of method for Prize Fund picture selection, October 29, 1885 (Reel 4821, Frame 440-445)
  - Art Related Expenses, 1884-1919, undated, 5.2:
    - Art related expenses--miscellaneous receipts for expenses, pictures purchased, insurance values, estimate of repairs for frames and conservation by James Kelly; statement of sales of Glasgow pictures, undated, 1884-1919 (Reel 4821, Frame 446-485)
    - Art related expenses--promissary notes, list of miscellaneous pictures and valuations (Reel 4821, Frame 486-493)
    - Art related expenses--receipts for pictures and purchases of decorative arts objects, 1890-1893 (Reel 4821, Frame 494-509)
    - Art related expenses, 1894 (Reel 4821, Frame 510-523)
    - Art related expenses--custom receipts, Glasgow and Danish School paintings, 1895 (Reel 4821, Frame 524-546)
    - Art related expenses--notes on buyers at Stewart sale, 1898 with purchase prices; amended estimate of account necessary for Department of Fine Arts, U.S. Commission to Paris Exposition of 1900, 1896-1899 (Reel 4821, Frame 547-601)
    - Art related expenses--list of Charles M. Kurtz pictures stored in St. Louis Art Museum with purchase date and price, insurance valuation and crate location list, 1900-1905 (Reel 4821, Frame 602-638)
    - Art related expenses--insurance policy, 1906-1910 (Reel 4821, Frame 639-661)
  - Miscellaneous Expenses, 1880-1948, undated, 5.4:
    - Miscellaneous expenses--notebook mislabeled "Private Picture Business" is list of personal household possessions and supplies, undated (Reel 4821, Frame 662-679)
    - Miscellaneous expenses--travel expense accounts, undated (Reel 4821, Frame 682-707)
    - Miscellaneous expenses--estimates, receipts, lists of books and personal possessions, undated (Reel 4821, Frame 708-724)
    - Miscellaneous expenses--accounts for personal living expenses, undated (Reel 4821, Frame 725-743)
    - Miscellaneous expenses--invoice statements by Charles M. Kurtz listing articles he wrote for New York Tribune, 1880 (Reel 4821, Frame 744-774)
    - Miscellaneous expenses--invoices for engravings for American Academy Notes, 1881 (Reel 4821, Frame 775-792)
    - Miscellaneous expenses--nvoices for Academy Notes and New York Tribune with clippings of some articles written by Charles M. Kurtz interspersed, 1882 (Reel 4821, Frame 793-835)
    - Miscellaneous expenses--invoices for Academy Notes and for miscellaneous items, 1883-1885 (Reel 4821, Frame 836-871)
    - Miscellaneous expenses--notebook labeled "Catalogue Sales" and "The Art Gallery, Southern Exposition, Louisville, Ky.," and invoices, 1886-1890 (Reel 4821, Frame 872-893)
    - Miscellaneous expenses, 1891 (Reel 4821, Frame 894-927)
    - Miscellaneous expenses, 1892 (Reel 4821, Frame 928-962)
    - Miscellaneous expenses, 1893 (Reel 4821, Frame 963-978)
    - Miscellaneous expenses--financial statement, "Expense of Bringing Foreign Paintings to Exposition," 1895, and invoices, 1894-1896 (Reel 4821, Frame 979-1000)
    - Miscellaneous expenses, 1897 (Reel 4821, Frame 1000-1029)
    - Miscellaneous expenses--miscellaneous travel receipts, 1898-1899 (Reel 4821, Frame 1030-1041)
    - Miscellaneous expenses--receipts from Paris trip, 1900 (Reel 4821, Frame 1042-1075)
    - Miscellaneous expenses, 1901 (Reel 4821, Frame 1076-1087)
    - Miscellaneous expenses--expense accounts for travel on behalf of the Louisiana Purchase Exposition, 1902-1905 (Reel 4821, Frame 1088-1118)
    - Miscellaneous expenses--invoice for cash advanced for the First Annual Exhibition of American Artists, Buffalo Fine Arts Academy, 1906-1909 (Reel 4821, Frame 1119-1134)
    - Miscellaneous expenses, 1908 (Reel 4821, Frame 1135-1173)
    - Miscellaneous expenses, 1909-1948 (Reel 4821, Frame 1174-1187)
    - Annotated checklist and catalogue of estate sale of Charles M. Kurtz collection with some prices (Reel 4825, Reel 4821, Frame 398-516)
- Diaries, 1894-1901, Series 6:
  For an individual as precise and meticulous as Kurtz was, this seems to be an unusually incomplete series. It consists of only five small books that record his activities for parts of only four years: 1894, 1897, 1899, and 1901. Kurtz himself gives an explanation for the lack of any diaries that date from before his marriage. In a letter, probably written in October, 1885, to his new bride, Julia Stephenson Kurtz, he writes "...our trunks have been broken open. My coins are gone. Diaries and memoranda books gone and nearly everything not destroyed seems to be ruined..."
  - March 10-May 6, 1894 (Reel 4822, Frame 001-034)
    (daily log of Charles M.Kurtz's trip abroad from March 10 to May 6, 1894; his activities in Gibraltar, Tangier, Cadiz, Seville, Cordova, Grenada, Madrid, Toledo, Barcelona, Naples, and Rome are described in detail; daily expenses are also recorded)
  - January 1-December 31, 1897 (Reel 4822, Frame 035-142)
    (daily account of Charles M. Kurtz's family life in New York City including the final illness and death of his eldest daughter and a chronicle of his own health problems; also entries describing their activities on a trip abroad to Scotland, France, Belgium and Amsterdam)
  - February 1-March 24, 1899 (Reel 4822, Frame 143-165)
    (some entries are labeled with headings, including: Century Club, Lotos "Saturday Night," Private View of T.B. Clarke pictures, Architectural League reception, Water Color Society reception, Whitlaw Reid Dinner at the Lotos Club, Reception at Franzen's to Bessie Potter, T. B. Clarke sale, Architectural League meeting, The Havemeyer Sale, Sons of Revolution Dinner with S.P.Avery, and Lotos Club Art Reception; also a synopsis of Kurtz's account, February 1899, with Reid Northrop for expert examination and purchases)
  - March, 1899 (Reel 4822, Frame 166-178)
    (entries labeled: Dinner Architectural League and Sculpture Society; and Society of American Artists Reception)
  - January 1-March 10, 1901 (Reel 4822, Frame 179-202)
    (functions as daily calendar of activities and expenses, no exposition; entries labeled: Dinner Arts Club; Watercolor "Stag" reception; Watercolor reception Arts Club; Dinner Architectural League; Zorn Exhibition, "Tea" Arts Club; Eastman Johnson Dinner at Lotos Club)
  - Miscellaneous Diary Pages, undated [after 1893] (Reel 4822, Frame 424-425)
    (notations regarding Glasgow School artists)
- Notes and Writings, 1872-1980, undated, Series 7:
  Perhaps because of his peripatetic lifestyle, Charles Kurtz kept very precise records. Included in this series are various types of lists, both personal and professional, as well as notes to himself. Drafts and fragments of lectures and his play The Millennium and his two comic operas, The Aldermen of Manhattan and The Cannibals! are also found within this series. Among the most interesting writings pertaining to the art world are the artist address lists, which are also broken down according to studio buildings (the Tenth Street Studio Building, the Sherwood, the Rembrandt, and the Y.M.C.A.), lists of artist models, dealers, and editors and detailed diagrams for the installation of the Glasgow School exhibition.
  A notebook belonging to Charles M. Kurtz and now owned by Yale University was loaned to the Archives for microfilming. Reel 4912 requires permission from Yale University in order to quote, publish or reproduce. It contains about a fifty page history of art in Scotland and the Glasgow School written by Kurtz in 1891 and revised in 1895.
  Reels 4822-4823 contain the bulk of his writings, however miscellaneous pieces (and references to them) can also be found in some of his letters, particularly to his wife.
  - Poem sent to Proctor and Gamble Co. on Ivory Soap (Reel 4812, Frame 56)
  - Poem written about the German steamship, Columbia (Reel 4813, Frame 794-797)
  - Poem To My Departed Kidney, Oct. 27, 1899 (Reel 4816, Frame 953)
  - Poem Lesé Majestie, Dec. 22, 1899 (Reel 4816, Frame 1017)
  - Excerpts from Hans Christian Anderson, Robert Southey, in Charles M. Kurtz's hand (Reel 4817, Frame 1003-1006)
  - Verses describing food aboard ship (Reel 4818, Frame 858)
  - Wedding invitation list (Reel 4822, Frame 209-214)
  - U.S. addresses of family and friends, undated (Reel 4822, Frame 215-16)
  - Paris addresses (Reel 4822, Frame 217)
  - Lists of artists, art administrators, dignitaries and collectors written on Columbian Exposition stationery (Reel 4822, Frame 218-230)
  - Membership list of the "Tabard" (Reel 4822, Frame 231)
  - List of New York Newspapers (Reel 4822, Frame 232-33)
  - Address books re: distribution of catalogues, undated, (4 vols.) (Reel 4822)
    - Distribution list for [the Crabbe?] catalogue (Reel 4822, Frame 234-240)
    - Writings, address books, artists, undated (Reel 4822, Frame 241)
    - New York artists address list (Reel 4822, Frame 242-246)
    - Address books, "Book of the Artists" and index of artists and their addresses, undated (Reel 4822, Frame 247-274)
    - Address book with addresses for artist models and sightseeing list, "New York for Visitors," 1873 [and later] (Reel 4822, Frame 275-341)
  - Address books, 1881 [and later] 1881-1883, (8 vols.) (Reel 4822, Frame 343-423)
    (includes artists directory, 1881; personal expenses, Feb. 2-Dec. 31, 1883; lists of artists by studio location; circulars sent, 1883; personal expenses [some entries by Mrs. Charles M. Kurtz]; contents of "little Paris trunk" and others; advertising, 1882; copies [of catalogues?] sent, 1881)
  - Address books, 1896 (Reel 4822, Frame 427-478)
    (New York addresses of art dealers and art editors)
  - Miscellaneous memo pages containing Glasgow entries, circa 1894-1905 (Reel 4822, Frame 483-502)
  - Note fragments, undated (Reel 4822, Frame 503-520)
    (miscellaneous notes regarding lectures, short story, medication schedule, theater)
  - Notes on art, undated (Reel 4822, Frame 521-525)
    (exhibition schedules)
  - Notes, undated (Reel 4822, Frame 526-541)
    (gallery plans - exhibition installations - for J.G. Brown, Glasgow School, Klackner's Gallery exhibitions; plan for "An Ideal City;" sketch for bookcases)
  - Notes on art, undated (Reel 4822, Frame 542-567)
    (lists of artists and their work; list of works from the Paris Salon desired by the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts; list of drawings not catalogued but for sale with prices; sculptors list; unidentified installation diagram and corresponding key to works of art for [1893 Chicago World's Fair]; list of D. F. Hasbrouck paintings)
  - Notes on art, undated (Reel 4822, Frame 568-596)
    (list of artists, paintings, and their addresses; draft for biographical sketches of Montesquieu, Massillon, G.W. Morrison, Nicola Masschall)
  - Notes, 1884-1890 (Reel 4822, Frame 597-606)
    (fragments; list of books; list of paintings with prices)
  - Notebook, 1891 (Reel 4822, Frame 607-642)
    (miscellaneous notes on characteristics of the French; expenses for the World's Columbian Exposition, 1865; letter to a relative; genealogy of Charles M. Kurtz's family; sketches for Prix de Rome competition; diary entry on London trip; unfilmed poem draft The Cannibals! An Original Comic Opera)
  - Notes, ca 1893 (Reel 4822, Frame 643-669)
    (miscellaneous notations written on World's Columbian Exposition stationery; drafts for lectures or articles)
  - Notes, circa 1893 (Reel 4822, Frame 670-676)
    (lists of artist names)
  - Notes, 1893 (Reel 4822, Frame 677-699)
    (incomplete gallery lists; Chicago Exposition notations concerning the size of the main building and space allotted to various countries)
  - Notes, 1893 (Reel 4822, Frame 700-702)
    (gallery floor plans with square footage for Fine Arts Building, Palace of Fine Arts, Chicago Exposition)
  - Notes, 1894 (Reel 4822, Frame 703-708)
    (weight list for Glasgow and Danish paintings, lists of artists and works for St. Louis Exposition)
  - Notes, St. Louis Exposition hanging plans, 1894 (Reel 4822, Frame 709-714)
    (hanging plans for art gallery: numbered diagrams for placement of paintings and for the Water Color Gallery)
  - Note, St. Louis Exposition diagrams and exhibition plans, 1895 (Reel 4822, Frame 715-725)
    (diagrams for placement of paintings including those by the Glasgow School and American artists)
  - Notes, 1896 (Reel 4822, Frame 726-730)
    (diagrams for the American and Glasgow paintings exhibited in Art Gallery at St. Louis Exposition)
  - Notes, gallery plans for St. Louis Exposition, 1897 (Reel 4822, Frame 731-736)
    (diagrams for placement of paintings with identifying numbers but no corresponding key)
  - Shipping and storage information, St. Louis Exposition, 1897 (Reel 4822, Frame 737-738)
  - Notes, 1898-1899 (Reel 4822, Frame 739-748)
    (catalogue data, 1898, and miscellaneous artists biographies)
  - Notes, circa 1900 (Reel 4822, Frame 749-752)
    (list of nations and types of art contributed to 1876 Centennial vs. World's Fair, 1900)
  - Notes, circa 1901 (Reel 4822, Frame 753-757)
    (proposal for selling picture "The Castelane Scheme")
  - Notes, 1904-circa 1909 (Reel 4822, Frame 758-763)
    (list of artists and assignments re: Louisiana Purchase Exposition; list of masterworks; personal medical notations)
  - Notes by Isabel Kurtz, circa 1980 (Reel 4822, Frame 764-775)
    (list of Glasgow School paintings at St. Louis Exposition, 1895, and subsequent exhibitions thru 1906 with bibliography)
  - Notes and writings, 1872, undated (Reel 4822, Frame 793-1337)
    (drafts of lectures: Art and the Nations, The Influence of the Fine Arts, and Art: Its, Evolution, Influence, and Mission; fragments of writings for The Tribune; Bunco Picture Dealing; notes on history of coin collecting; L'Art Nouveau, The Irresponsible in Art; General Art Notes; Christ Before Pilot; Christ on Calvary; The Collectors Club with the Bric-a-Brac Club; draft, information for visitors to the United States section; The Metropolitan Museum on the Question of Sunday Opening; English Stately Homes; miscellaneous notations on foreign paintings with comments; Some Art Talk; The First Exhibition of the Society of American Artists; poem, L'Envoy; draft of account of Kurtz's trip to Italy, 1881; Kind Words, The American Art Union; untitled draft on American architecture and national characteristics; Extract from Semple letter on Protective Art Society; What Is Art?; lecture course for 1892-93, St Louis Museum of Art; Art In St. Louis, 1898 (signed Stuart MacDonald); art building exhibit space; poem to Zolnay; list of names of commissioners from foreign countries; The St. Louis World's Fair of 1904 - lecture; Department of Art Awards to Exhibitors; text for informational circulars to artists)
  - Miscellaneous notes and writings, 1872-1908, undated (Reel 4822, Frame 1340)
    (My Last Day in Paris; Garfield's Assassination; The "Company" in a Clock; creative writing exercises; The Reviewer; A Strange Interview; Thurlow Weed editorial; The Stone Fort Club; The Festive Microbes (signed Ch. Breve); A Brave Little Soldier, A Story of War Time; The Chimpanzee and the Ass, A Fable; The Three Blind Mice, A Sermon; A Month in Massachusetts; The Artist and the Philanthropists, - - short story)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1872-1908, undated (Reel 4823, Frame 1-249)
    (miscellaneous poems, untitled and Will H. Low; Madame Quarante-neuf; Before the Beginning; The Banker Prince; Good News; To A Lady Singing in a Church Choir; A Greeting; War's Newest Terror; Trumpet Calls; (C. A. Price) An Ode Owed to Mr. C. M. Kurtz by J. F. Riley; The Life of Adam notebook; Selections from Original Poems, New York, 1877; undated list of questions and answers about an impending election and the outlook for the Republican Party in Pennsylvania; Prophetic Spirits - draft of a report on spiritualist meeting; New York, 1880; The Aldermen of Man-hat-tan, An Original Comic Opera; The Cannibals! An Original Comic Opera - typescript and 1892 libretto; miscellaneous poems by Charles M. Kurtz)
  - Poem [untitled], August 9, 1889 (Reel 4823, Frame 223-224)
    (written in Charles M. Kurtz's hand, possibly a reflection of his personal situation: "I think you're wrong for letters, you're in debt")
  - Smythe's Song from Charles M. Kurtz's comic opera, The Cannibals (Reel 4823, Frame 267-268)
- Scrapbooks, 1878-1909, Series 8:
  The scrapbooks that Charles M. Kurtz compiled over the course of his life form an overview of his professional career. Beginning with his early writings on art and continuing with reviews and clippings of exhibitions and expositions that he was involved with, the scrapbooks highlight Kurtz's various activities in the art world.
  - Scrapbook I, 1878-1882 (Reel 4823, Frame 253-337)
    (1878-1879 clippings from The Courant, The Guardian and other regional newspapers, primarily written by Charles M. Kurtz; miscellaneous loose clippings and reviews; "Art Notes" in The Tribune by Charles M. Kurtz beginning October 8, 1882)
  - Scrapbook II: "Southern Expos., 1885-86" (sic), [1885-88] (Reel 4823, Frame 338-412)
    (clippings and memorabilia relating to the Southern Exposition at Louisville, Kentucky; clippings from various newspapers of Kurtz's art columns; reviews of exhibitions curated by Kurtz; Exposition Advance Book; reviews of Christ Before Pilot travelling exhibition)
  - Scrapbook III, The Star, Feb. 24, 1889-May 14, 1889 (Reel 4823, Frame 413-492)
    (list of articles contributed to The Star, with publication dates; clippings of articles that appeared in The Star)
  - Scrapbook IV, The Star, August 26, 1889-April 29, 1890 (Reel 4823, Frame 493-577)
    (articles contributed to The Star)
  - Scrapbook V, 1891 (Reel 4823, Frame 578-611)
    (articles contributed to The World, The New York Recorder, New York Truth, The Times)
  - Scrapbook VI, 1890-1891 (Reel 4823, Frame 612-695)
  - Scrapbook VII, 1891-1894 (Reel 4823, Frame 696-739)
    (articles contributed to Chicago Evening Post; 1894 articles for the New York Herald; The New York Times; 1891-1893 articles for The Chicago Graphic; miscellaneous artists biographies found in scrapbook; 1894 articles for The Graphic)
  - Scrapbook VIII, 1893-1894 (Reel 4823, Frame 740-771)
    (St. Louis Exposition and Music Hall Association clippings and memorabilia)
  - Scrapbook IX, 1895 (Reel 4823, Frame 772-812)
    (St. Louis Exposition and Music Hall Association memorabilia; clippings of Glasgow School and Danish School)
  - Scrapbook X, 1905-1906 (Reel 4823, Frame 813-910)
    (1905 dedication of The Albright Art Gallery, Buffalo, New York and related clippings and memorabilia, 1905-1906 including accounts of controversies between Charles M. Kurtz and the Carnegie Institute and the Metropolitan Museum of Art; issue of Die Werkstatt der Kunst in German)
  - Scrapbook XI, 1907-1908 (Reel 4823, Frame 913-960, Reel 4824, Frame 001-037)
    (clippings of reviews of modern German Art exhibition and subsequent discussions on sales of duty free pictures; issue of Die Werkstatt der kunst in German; reviews of work by Genjiro Yeto, F. Hopkinson Smith; clippings and reviews relating to exhibitions at the Albright Art Gallery including French Impressionists, Photo-Pictorialists, Hugh H. Breckinridge, Timothy Cole, Harrington Mann; and clippings related to the controversy on museums functioning as picture dealers)
  - Scrapbook XII, 1908-1909 (Reel 4824, Frame 038-103)
    (clippings and reviews relating to exhibitions and events at the Albright Art Gallery including Howard Russell Butler, Photographs of Native American Indians by Edward B. Curtis, Antonio Corsi visit, pictures by Buffalo women, Edmund C. Tarbell, Childe Hassam, F.K.M. Rehn, Wm. M. Chase, Ignacio Zuloaga, lectures by Kurtz on Wm. M. Chase, James Whistler, Spanish art; letter, in Spanish, from J. Sorolla y Bastida, and obituaries for Charles M. Kurtz)
- Printed Material, 1873-1990, undated, Series 9:
  The majority of printed material can be found on microfilm reels numbered 4824 and 4825. However the correspondence does contain some individual articles that were enclosed in letters. These miscellaneous items are listed preceding the majority of the printed matter on the aforementioned two reels. Some duplicates of the catalogs found in this series were not filmed.
  - Clippings reviewing Munkacsy exhibition, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 1238-1242)
  - Clippings regarding Munkacsy exhibition, 1886 (Reel 4807, Frame 1315-1319)
  - Description of Munkacsy's "Christ Before Pilot" from the illustrated handbook that accompanied the exhibition, 1886 (Reel 4808, Frame 760-64)
  - Description of Munkacsy's companion picture, "Christ on Calvary" (Reel 4808, Frame 796-797)
  - Checklist of the Charles M. Kurtz Collection loaned for exhibition at "The Sketch Club," 1887 (Reel 4808, Frame 900-902)
  - Ticket for Munkacsy's "Christ on Calvary" exhibition (Reel 4808, Frame 1208-09)
  - Catalogue/checklist for Jervis McEntee sale at Fifth Avenue Art Galleries, March, 1888 (Reel 4808, Frame 1249-1255)
  - Illustrations and announcement for National Academy Notes, 1888 (Reel 4808, Frame 1423-26)
  - Biographical account of the American cattle painter, Mrs. Emily J. Lakey (Reel 4808, Frame 1427)
  - Illustrated postcard "Centennial Exposition of the Ohio Valley and Central States at Cincinnati," 1888 (Reel 4809, Frame 15)
  - Review of exhibition by Emily Lakey (Reel 4809, Frame 29)
  - Review of Munkacsy's "Christ Before Pilate" (Reel 4809, Frame 263-265)
  - Obituary of Carl Brenner (Reel 4809, Frame 266)
  - Checklist for sale of paintings collected by Kurtz and Sedelmeyer (Reel 4809, Frame 300-302)
  - Flyer from St. Louis Exposition, Munkacsy's "Christ on Calvary" (Reel 4809, Frame 380)
  - 3 cards illustrated with pictures from firm Redheffer & Koch, Art Dealers (Reel 4809, Frame 470)
  - Review of novel (Reel 4809, Frame 596)
  - Card of admittance for Munkacsy's "Christ on Calvary" and "Christ Before Pilate" (Reel 4809, Frame 599, 709)
  - Description of Munkacsy's "Christ on Calvary-The Moral Show" (Reel 4809, Frame 736)